William P. McDermott Railroad Collection
© 2011 University of Connecticut
William P. McDermott Railroad Collection.
1835-1903.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
McDermott, William P.
3 linear feet.
The collection consists of payroll vouchers, traffic vouchers, correspondence, deposit slips, financial documents and other materials associated with the Hartford & New Haven Railroad, the Central New England Railway, the Philadephia, Reading & New England Railroad, the New York & Boston Railroad and other railroad lines in southern New England and eastern New York. Some of the correspondence is to John Brock, president of the Central New England Railway.
MSS20060180
Biography
William P. McDermott is a resident of Tolland, Connecticut. The Hartford & New Haven Railroad was incorporated in 1833 and organized in 1835. The Hartford, Providence & Fishkill Railroad was formed and organized in 1849 by a consolidation of the New York & Hartford Railroad and the Hartford & Providence Railroad. It was deeded in 1863 to the Boston, Hartford & Erie Railroad. The Philadelphia, Reading & New England Railroad formed in 1892 by the consolidation of the Central New England and Western Railroad and the Poughkeepsie Bridge and Railroad Company. The property and franchises were sold in 1898 to become the Central New England Railway. The Central New England Railway was incorporated 1899 with its principal office in Poughkeepsie, New York. The New York & New England Railroad was formed in 1873 by bondholders of the Boston, Hartford & Erie Railroad; all property deeded to the New England Railroad in 1895. In 1872 the New York & New Haven Railroad consolidated with the Hartford & New Haven Railroad to become the New York, New Haven and Hartford Railroad.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of payroll vouchers, traffic vouchers, correspondence, deposit slips, financial documents and other materials associated with the Hartford & New Haven Railroad, the Central New England Railway, the Philadephia, Reading & New England Railroad, the New York & Boston Railroad and other railroad lines in southern New England and eastern New York. Much of the correspondence is to John Brock, president of the Central New England Railway.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to the New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad and its predecessor lines, including the Central New England Railway, and other railroads of southern New England. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Persons:
Brock, John
Organizations:
Central New England Railway.; Central New England and Western Railroad.; Philadelphia, Reading & New England Railroad.; Providence & Worcester Railroad.; New York & New England Railroad.; New Haven & Derby Railroad.; New York & Boston Railroad.; Hartford & New Haven Railroad.; New York & Massachusetts Railway.; Providence & Springfield Railroad.; Hartford, Providence & Fishkill Railroad.; New York & New Haven Railroad.
Places:
Rhinebeck [N.Y.]; Rhinecliff [N.Y.]; Poughkeepsie [N.Y.]
Subjects:
Railroads -- New York.; Railroads -- Connecticut.
Document Types:
Correspondence.; Administrative Records.; Financial Records.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
The collection was donated by William P. McDermott in 2006.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Railroad Collection, 1835-1903
  - Central New England Railway payroll vouchers, 1900-1902 (Box 1:, Folder 1-2)
  - Central New England Railway payroll vouchers, 1900-1903 (Box 1:, Folder 3)
  - Central New England Railway traffic vouchers, 1899-1903 (Box 2:, Folder 4-5)
  - Central New England Railway time certificates for employees leaving service, 1899-1903 (Box 2:, Folder 6)
  - Central New England and Western Railroad earnings and expense sheets, 1889-1890 (Box 3:, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence to John Brock of the Central New England Railway about a bridge between Rhinebeck and Rhinecliff, New York, 1899 (Box 3:, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence to John Brock about trip and annual passes and the Poughkeepsie Bridge Route, 1899 (Box 3:, Folder 9)
  - Central New England Railway accounts payable sheets, 1900-1903 (Box 3:, Folder 10)
  - Central New England Railway coal vouchers, 1891, 1899-1901 (Box 3:, Folder 11)
  - Petitions to the Board of Directors of the Hartford & New Haven Railroad, from farmers and businessmen in Connecticut asking that the railroad be constructed in such a way as to pass through their towns, 1835-1836 (Box 4:, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence to the Hartford & New Haven Railroad regarding stock purchases, 1835 (Box 4:, Folder 13)
  - Subscriptions to the Hartford & New Haven Railroad to raise money to defray building costs and for a preliminary survey, 1835 (Box 4:, Folder 14)
  - Claims of damage or payment, to the Hartford & New Haven Railroad, for land taken by the railroad, 1836-1840 (Box 4:, Folder 15)
  - Summary statements of estimated costs associated with the Hartford & New Haven Railroad, 1837-1838 (Box 4:, Folder 16)
  - Legal and financial documents associated with the Hartford & New Haven Railroad, 1843-1844 (Box 4:, Folder 17)
  - Financial documents associated with the New York & Massachusetts Railway, 1888-1889 (Box 4:, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence from vendors and other businesses to John Brock, president of the Philadephia, Reading & New England Railroad and the Central New England Railway, and other officials on goods and services needed for the railroad, 1890-1899 (Box 5:, Folder 19)
  - Stock dividends of the New York & New Haven Railroad, 1851, 1864-1867 (Box 5:, Folder 20)
  - Accounts payable and traffic vouchers of the Philadephia, Reading & New England Railroad, 1893-1901 (Box 5:, Folder 21-22)
  - Financial documents and information about ticket collecting associated with the Hartford & New Haven Railroad and the New York & New Haven Railroad, 1840s-1860s (Box 5:, Folder 23)
  - Payroll and financial documents of the Philadelphia, Reading & New England Railroad, 1893-1894 (Box 6:, Folder 24)
  - Financial and legal documents of the Hartford & New Haven Railroad and the New York & Boston Railroad, 1835-1843 (Box 6:, Folder 25)
  - Financial documents of the Philadelphia, Reading & New England Railroad, the Providence & Worcester Railroad, New York & New England Railroad, New Haven & Derby Railroad, Central New England Railway, and the New York & Boston Railroad, 1849-1906 (Box 6:, Folder 26)
  - Receipts and freight reports of the Providence & Springfield Railroad, 1883, 1890 (Box 6:, Folder 27)
  - Payroll and traffic vouchers and financial documents of the Philadelphia, Reading & New England Railroad, the Central New England Railway, and the Hartford, Providence & Fishkill Railroad, 1898-1901 (Box 6:, Folder 28)